---
title: Openenv Rl Trainer
emoji: 🚀
colorFrom: blue
colorTo: indigo
sdk: docker
app_file: main.py
pinned: false
---
# OpenEnv RL Trainer

This folder contains a fully modular, plug-and-play Reinforcement Learning (RL) training pipeline for the OpenEnv Contract Review benchmark.

## Architecture

The project is structured using clean Software Design Principles (Separation of Concerns, Dependency Injection, Modularity).

### Files:
- \`main.py\`: The plug-and-play entrypoint orchestrating the experiment.
- \`src/config.py\`: Centralized hyperparameters and settings.
- \`src/env_client.py\`: Handles HTTP communication with the Hugging Face space.
- \`src/agent.py\`: The AI Agent containing the LLM, tokenization, and RL optimization logic (Policy Gradient).
- \`src/evaluation.py\`: Logic for running blind evaluations, collecting metrics, and plotting graphs.

## How to Run

1. **Install requirements:**
   \`\`\`bash
   pip install -r requirements.txt
   \`\`\`
   *(Note: \`trl\` is removed to avoid version and import conflicts. This project uses vanilla PyTorch Policy Gradients to demonstrate the exact math of RL without dependency bloat.)*

2. **Set your environment variable (if your space requires authentication):**
   Add an \`.env\` file in this folder with \`API_KEY=\` if needed.

3. **Run the experiment:**
   \`\`\`bash
   python main.py
   \`\`\`

## What It Does
- Evaluates the "untrained" model on the hard task to establish a baseline.
- Trains the model on the easy and medium tasks using a trial-and-error Policy Gradient update (updating the neural network weights based on the reward score).
- Evaluates the "trained" model on the hard task again.
- Generates a graph (\`training_results.png\`) comparing performance!
